(ブラミ)ニオッちゃった。
I just caught a whiff...
(ムヤミ)ようやく自分の
臭いニオイに気づいたのかよ。
You finally notice
what you smell like?
おいらのじゃなくて。
Not me.
知ってるっしょ？
When you deal with things
that smell,
臭いもの系扱う者は➡
他のニオイにも敏感だって。
your nose becomes sensitive
to all kinds of scents.
(カザミ)何のニオイだ？
What do you smell?
(ブラミ)あの いちばんうるさいやつ。
The loud-mouthed guy.
犬臭いから すぐわかる。
I'd recognize
his mongrel smell anywhere.
やつら あの砂から
出てきたというのか？
Them...?!
Are you telling me they managed
to climb out of the sand?!
(ブラミ)生きてたほうが
おもしろくていいじゃない。
It's more fun this way.
追いかけっこだよ 鬼ごっこだよ。
We're back to the chase!
We can play tag!
僕は全然
おもしろくないんだけど…。
It's no fun for me at all.
(カザミ)やつらが どうあがこうと➡
– No matter how hard they try,
– This place is so hot and open.
俺たちに追いつくことなど
できるはずもないが。
– they can't catch up to us.
– Give me a nice corner to snuggle up in.
だったら この手でいくか。
Then let's do this.
(ブラミ)ヘヘヘヘ かわいそうな木ノ葉。
Poor Hidden Leaf.
ブ～ラミ～。
Bu... rami!
よし ブラミにエールを送ろう。
All right...
Let's cheer for Burami!
フレ～ フレ～ ブラミ！
Hip hip hurray! Burami!
オ～ フレッ フレッ ブラミ！
Hip hip hooray! Burami!
フレッ フレッ ブラミ！
かぁ～！
うわぁ こ これやなんだよ。
I hate this so much!
くっ。
ヘヘヘ これでおいらたちの
ニオイは中和された。
This will neutralize our smell.
無臭だ。
We're odorless.
(キバ)ニオイが消えた。
(赤丸)ワンワン！
Their scent is gone!
お前もそうか クソッ。
You too?
Damn it!
(ヒナタ)どうしよう…。
(シノ)絶望する理由はない。
What'll we do?
There's no reason to despair.
なぜなら嗅覚がダメなら視覚がある。
That's because if we lose
our sense of smell,
we still have the sense of sight.
でも相手は白眼の圏外に。
But they're outside the range
of the Byakugan!
だったら 圏内に
こちらから行けばいい。
Then we have to get within range.
(キバ)頼むぜ 蟲たち！
We're counting on you, insects!
あの先でやつらの姿を
見つけたらしい。
Looks like they found
those guys up ahead.
見てろよ 俺たちの巻物。
All right, just watch!
We're getting back the scroll...
いや 天と地の両方とも
奪い返してやるからよ！
I mean, both the Heaven
and Earth scrolls!
Ready, set, go, we step over the goal line
isse nou se de fumikomu gourain
Still, we don't know anything at all
bokura wa nanimo nanimo mada shiranu
We look back as we pass the line, and it's already gone
issen koete furikaeruto mou nai
Still, we don't know anything at all
bokura wa nanimo nanimo mada shiranu
Fiercely, fiercely we move on
udatte udatte udatteku
Drenched in glistening sweat
kirameku ase ga koboreru no sa
There probably were a lot of things we didn't remember
oboetenai koto mo takusan atta darou
Everyone was just a silhouette
daremo kare mo shiruetto
Let's become adults,
daiji ni shitai mono motte otona ni naru nda
holding on to things we want to cherish
And let's keep on protecting them at all times
donna toki mo hanasazu ni mamori tsudzukeyou
Then someday...
soshitara itsu no hi ni ka
We'll be able to laugh at it all
nanimo kamo o waraerusa
Like the light and nimble dancing
hirari to hirari to matteru
Of leaves taking flight
konoha ga tonde yuku
Unwavering Gutsiness
あれだ。
There they are.
よっしゃ！ 今度はやつらが
砂にまみれる番だぜ。
Now it's their turn to sink into sand!
(ヒナタ)待って。
Wait...
(ヒナタ)チャクラが見えない。
I don't see their chakra.
なっ どういうことだ!?
What? What do you mean?
蜃気楼…。
It's a mirage...
クッソ～！
Damn it...
(キバ)ニセモノかよ。
So they're fakes?
あっ。
塔か。
The tower...
(ヒナタ)もう一度 シノ君の蟲たちで。
Use your insects again, Shino...
だが 本物が見つかる確信はない。
But there's no guarantee
we'll find the real guys.
(シノ)蟲たちの連絡を待つ間に➡
There's a chance
they'll reach the tower
やつらが塔にたどり着いて
しまうこともありうる。
while we wait for
my insects to respond.
クッソ。
Damn it!
《なんであいつが》
Why does his face
keep popping up?
キバ君？
Kiba?
(キバ)諦めねえ…。
We can't give up.
追うんだよ やつらを。
Let's go after them.
(シノ)手がかりもなく
ただ闇雲に追おうというのか？
Even if we have no clue
where they are?
手がかりがないわけじゃねえ！
Sure we have a clue!
(キバ)やつらが塔を
目指しているのは間違いねえし➡
It's guaranteed they're heading
for the tower.
あの底なしの砂場のある地帯は
避けていくだろう。
And they're going to avoid
that bottomless swamp!
広くったって 範囲は範囲だ。
It's a huge perimeter, I know...
But it's still a set range!
ヒナタ どうだ？
Well, Hinata?
せめて 方角だけでも
絞れねえか？
Can you at least try
to get a direction?
うん やってみる。
Okay, I'll try.
(ヒナタ)白眼！
Byakugan!
北東の辺りは 流砂が多そう。
Looks like there's lots
of quicksand in the northeast.
北西は もっと絞れる。
The northwest is...
even more restricted.
(ヒナタ)北北東からなら
比較的 安全なルートだと思う。
In comparison, the north-northeast
route looks safer...
塔に向かうのは賛成だ。
やつらの他にも➡
I'm in favor of heading
for the tower.
There's also the chance
of finding others
天地の巻物を持った者たちが
いる可能性は大きい。
with the Heaven and Earth scrolls.
あの３人にこだわる必要はない。
We don't have to target
the Hidden Grass trio.
あるっつうんだよ！
Yes, we do!
(キバ)やつらは 俺たちの巻物を
奪っていったんだ。
Those guys stole our scroll.
俺から！ ナルトだったら やつらから
ぜってえ取り返すだろ。
I would...
Naruto would absolutely
take it back from them!
ナルト？
(キバ)あ… いや➡
Naruto?
ナルトはどうでもいい。
ううん ナルト君なら諦めない。
I mean, never mind Naruto.
You're right.
Naruto wouldn't give up.
どこまでもあの人たちを追って…。
He would pursue them to
the ends of the earth...
いや だからナルトじゃなくて俺！
Forget Naruto!
俺が諦めないんだよ！
I'm not going to give up!
そうだ ナルトは諦めない。
Right, Naruto wouldn't give up.
だから俺が！
I said I'm not...!
(シノ)いや 俺たちが… だ。
No, we won't.
シノ…。
Shino...
なぜなら 十班が感知能力で
敗北することは➡
That's because Team 8 with
its sensory perception powers
絶対あってはならないからだ。
must never be beaten.
シノ君。
Shino!
よっしゃ～！ 俺たちの意地
見せてやろうじゃねえかよ！
All right!
Let's show them
what we're made of!
(キバ)ぜってえ やつら逃がさねえ！
We're not letting them...
get away!
ん？
(カザミ)どうやら逃げ切れるぞ。
I think we gave them the slip.
ブブ～！
あ？ どうした？
What's wrong?
しつこい！
あいつら追ってきてる。
It's those pesky guys again.
ニオイは消したんじゃないのか？
I thought you erased our smell?
そうだよ たぶんだけど
あいつら➡
I did...
But it seems like
they can track by instinct.
勘で追ってきてるみたい。
じゃあ こっちが別ルートに
迂回していけばいいじゃないか。
Then let's just take a detour.
いや あいつらナメちゃダメだ。
No, we can't underestimate them.
確かに このしつこさは
ただ事ではない。
Their persistence isn't ordinary.
やつら 追跡のスキルに相当の自信を
持っているのかもしれん。
They must be really confident
about their tracking skills.
じゃあ どうすんの？
So, what'll we do?
おいらがいるから安心さ。
You have me, so relax.
フレ～！ フレ～！ ブラミ！
Hip hip hooray, Burami!
せや～！
Here we... go!
(赤丸)ワンワン！
(キバ)お前もか？ 赤丸。
(ヒナタ)どうしたの？ キバ君。
You too, Akamaru?!
What is it, Kiba?
(キバ)あの脂身野郎のニオイが
復活した！
It's that blubber man's smell!
こっちだ！
This way!
《ヘッ 隠そうとしたって
てめえのニオイは➡
You can try,
but you can't hide your smell!
隠せるもんじゃねえんだよ！
今 行くからよ 待って…》
I'll be there...
You just wait.
キバ君？
Kiba...
やはり罠か。
As expected, a trap.
どこもかしこも
やつのニオイだらけだ。
The whole place reeks
with his smell.
おら～！
どれがやつの本当のニオイだ？
Which smell...
is that bastard's smell?
あいつのニオイ…。
His smell?
やつらのほうが上手だったか。
They're on to us.
(キバ)クッソ…。
Damn it!
(赤丸)ク～ン…。
クッソ…。
Damn it!
《なんで笑っていられたんだ？
Why was I able to
keep laughing?
なんで 立ち上がれたんだ？
Why was I able to
get back up again?
あのとき 何がそうさせたんだ？》
What enabled me to do
that back then?
((キバ : ナルトのやつ
やっと追いついたと思ったら➡
Naruto...
Just when I thought
I caught up to him...
自来也様と修業の旅かよ。
He takes off to train
with Master Jiraiya...
クッソ… 俺だって。
Damn it...
Even I want...
いいか 赤丸！
Listen, Akamaru...
俺たちは 双頭狼の先を行く。
We're going to surpass
the Two-Headed Wolf.
すんげえ いっぱい
頭を増やすんだよ！
We're going to increase
the number of heads by a lot!
名づけて 多頭狼！
And we'll call it the...
Multi-Headed Wolf!
ク～ン。
そのためには➡
To do that...
影分身の術！
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
ワンワン！ ワンワン！
な… なんだ 全然 チャクラが…。
W-What...?
I don't have...
足りねえ。
enough chakra!
ワンワン！
わかったっつの。
そりゃ そうだよな。
Okay, I get it.
You're right...
影分身は 多ければ多いほど➡
The more Shadow Clones,
the more chakra you use up.
チャクラが分散されて
減っちまうんだもんな。
《ナルトのやつ
どんだけのチャクラを…》
I wonder how much chakra
Naruto has?
クッソ… しようがねえ
まずは １体から始めて➡
Damn it...
It's no use.
I've got to start with one,
then steadily increase it.
おいおい 増やしていくか！
ワン！
影分身の術！
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
いくぞ 赤丸！
お前 入れて３体だから➡
Let's do it, Akamaru!
Counting you, we'll have three bodies!
参頭狼だ！
Three-Headed Wolf!
犬塚流人獣混合変化！
– Inuzuka Style...
– Man Beast Transformation Combo!
参頭狼！
– Three-Headed Wolf!
チャクラが半分になるだけで
全然 術がもたねえなんて…。
I can't even sustain my jutsu
when my chakra goes down by half...
おいおい増やすどころじゃねえ。
Steadily increase it?
Who am I kidding?
参頭狼だって
できるかどうか…。
Can I even do
a Three-Headed Wolf...?
はぁ…。
やるんだ！
I have to do it!
やるんだ やるんだ やるんだ！
Do it! Do it! Do it!
《チャクラが足りねえなら
増やしてやる！
If I don't have enough chakra,
I'll increase it!
スタミナと体術で
基礎体力を上げるんだ！》
I'll work on my stamina
and taijutsu
うお～っ!!
to build up my basic strength!
ここは…。
This is...
あっ！
ナルト。
Naruto!
血と汗と➡
Blood, sweat...
ナルトのニオイに満ちてやがる。
This place reeks
with Naruto's scent...
(ナルト)おりゃ～っ！
(赤丸)ク～ン…。
お前もニオイでわかるか？
Can you tell by this scent?
俺もわかるぜ。
Me too.
あいつが どれだけ
すげえ修業をしてきたか。
I can tell just how hard
Naruto trained in here.
ここを
俺たちだけのニオイにしてやる。
I'm going to cover this place...
with our scent!
ワンワン！
影分身の術！
ワン！
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
ガオ～！
グッ！
キャンキャン！
もう一度やるぞ 赤丸。
ワンワン！
One more time, Akamaru!
《キバ : 諦めねえ
ぜってえ諦めねえ》
I won't give up!
I'm never giving up!
《負けてたまるか やつなんかに》
No way am I going to lose...
to that bastard!
(キバ)参頭狼！
Three-Headed Wolf!
ワン！
(ああ 俺の… 俺たちのニオイだ))
Yeah, it's my...
It's our scent!
クソ… ナルトを感じる。
Damn... I can feel Naruto.
またやつが笑ってる。
He's laughing at us again...
諦めるのかって。
Asking if we're gonna give up...
諦めねえさ。
We're not giving up.
諦めていいんだよ～！
It's okay...
Just give up!
お前ら… どうして…。
Y-You guys...
How... did...?
へっへへ 追われる者が➡
Nothing wrong with prey
turning into the predator, right?
追うほうになったって
いいじゃな～い？
クッ。
《まずい。
完全に不意をつかれた。
They totally caught us by surprise...
このままでは…》
At this rate...
フレ～！ フレ～！ ブラミ！
Hip hip hooray...
Burami!
オ～！ フレッ フレッ ムヤミ！
フレッ フレッ ブラミ！
Hip hip hooray,
Muyami!
Hip hip hooray, Burami!
《やっぱもうダメなのか。
Is it over... for us?
あっ… これって》
That's...!
グッ… あっ。
あれ？ 動かなくなっちゃった。
Hey, he stopped moving...
あっ。
やった～！
やつらを倒せたよ。
We did it!
We beat them!
おいらのおかげだい！
And it's all 'cuz of me!
違うぞ ブラミ
俺たちのチーム力の賜物だ。
No, Burami.
It was our teamwork.
どっちでもいいよ。
早く終わらせよう。
It doesn't matter.
Let's hurry and finish this.
行くぞ。
おいらのおかげだね。
Let's go.
It's all 'cuz of me!
(ブラミ)塔だ やったよ。
There's the tower!
We did it!
あん？
(カザミ)お前たち どうして。
You guys! How...?!
まんまと騙されやがってよ。
俺たちが死んだと思ったか？
We fooled you real good!
Did you think we were dead?!
どっこいこうして生きてるぜ。
Too bad...
We're still alive!
俺は 体内の蟲を使って
仮死状態となり…。
I used the insects inside me
to mimic a death-like state.
(シノ)キバとヒナタは
蟲分身と入れ替わった。
Kiba and Hinata switched places
with insect clones.
引っかかっちゃった！
We've been had!
だとしても なぜだ？
Even so? How were you
able to track us?!
なぜ俺たちを追ってこれた？
やつらのニオイに
気づかなかったのか？
Didn't you catch their scent?
俺たちのニオイは漏れなかった。
Our scent didn't leak.
なぜなら…。
The reason is...
(カザミ)蟲で 気密服を作っただと!?
You made airtight suits made
with your insects?!
ヘヘッ どうだ！
クッ。
How do you like that?!
でもさ でもさ おいらだって
またニオイを消したんだよ？
But, but... we erased our scent too!
あいつらが
追ってこられるわけないんだから。
So how come they were able
to track us?!
(キバ)お前のニオイなんか➡
We didn't follow your scent!
追ってきちゃいねえよ。
え？
俺は こいつのニオイを
追ってきたんだ。
I followed this scent!
ナルトってやつがいるんだがよ。
There's a guy named Naruto!
知らないよ 誰それ？
Never heard of him.
Who is he?!
そんなやつがいるんだよ！
I'm just saying he exists!
だからよ ナルトのこと
思い出してよ…。
And he kept popping
into my head.
おかしいとは思ってたんだが➡
I thought it was strange...
Then I remembered.
さっきわかったんだよ。
ニオイってやつは 記憶を
呼び覚ましやすいって言うだろ。
Different scents stir up
your memory.
((ガオ～！))
(キバ)あの練習場にあった
草の葉がこすれて➡
Back at that training ground,
some grass got rubbed into my elbow.
俺の肘にこびりついた。
そのニオイがあの訓練を…。
The scent of that reminded me
of that training...
思い出したくもねえナルトのことまで
思い出させやがったんだ。
and even brought back memories
I didn't want to remember... like Naruto!
フン どんなことがあっても
ぜってえ諦めるなってな。
Telling me not to give up,
no matter what.
僕たち関係ないし。
That's got nothing to do with us...
関係あんだよ！
But it does!
肘についた染みをな➡
The stain on my elbow...
さっき お肉ちゃんの
ドテッ腹につけさせてもらった。
I rubbed it on
Blubber Man's belly earlier.
えっ！
肉のニオイは消せても➡
You were able to erase
the scent of your flesh...
草のニオイには
気が回らなかったようだな。
but you didn't think as far as
erasing the smell of the grass.
お前のせいだ。
It's your fault.
いや チーム全体の責任だ。
No, it's the entire team's fault!
ヘッ 追いついたからには返して…。
Anyway, we caught up to you,
so return it...
いや 奪い取ってみせるぜ！
No... We'll take it back from you!
天地の巻物をな。
Our Heaven scroll!
口寄せの術… モグラン丸！
Summoning Jutsu!
Moguranmaru!
(モグラン丸)モグ～！
侵入 成功。
Infestation successful!
牙通牙！
Fang Over Fang!
うっ ブヨヨヨ… フン！
ブモ～！
食い破れ 寄大蟲。
Devour them!
Parasitic Gigantic Beetle!
あ～！
お～！
八卦空掌。
8 Trigrams: Air Palm!
うお～！
３人まとめて
ぶっ倒してやるぜ！
I'll take down all three
of you at once!
影分身の術！
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
犬塚流人獣混合変化。
Inuzuka Style...
Man Beast Transformation Combo!
参頭狼！
Three-Headed Wolf!
ブラミ！
だ 大丈夫 おいらが…。
Burami!
I'm okay! I'm...!
フ… フレ～！
H-Hip...
(キバ)尾追い。
フレ～！
Tail Chasing!
Hooray!!
(キバ)牙牙転牙！
Rotating Fang!
(ヒナタ)キバ君！
Kiba!
(シノ)ナルトに救われたな なぜなら…。
Naruto saved us...
That's because...
なぜなら やつの諦めない
ド根性を思い出したからってか？
That's because Naruto reminded us
to never give up!
You think?!
冗談じゃねえ！
やつの記憶から…。
Don't kid yourself!
I'm the one
who remembered Naruto,
こいつのニオイにたどり着き
利用したのは俺だ。
then tracked that guy
with his scent!
俺のおかげだぜ！
It was all 'cuz of me!
でも やっぱり ナルト君が。
I still think Naruto...
俺のおかげだっつうの。
ワン！
It was me!
(キバ)ハハッ 赤丸も頑張った。
You did great too, Akamaru!
(赤丸)ワオ～ン。
nando tatakitsukerarete mo
No matter how many times I get beat down
akiramerareru wake nado wanaku genten kaiki
I can't give up, so I go back to my basics
genjitsu to wa baibai shite
I wish we could say bye-bye to this reality
mukashi mitai ni waiwai shitai keredo
And have fun like we used to
sou mo ikanai nara kirihiraite mirya ii
But it doesn't work that way,
so let's carve out our own paths
nokori wazuka no shouki torimodoshite
I'll make you get back the little sanity you have left
me no mae no tobira kojiakete miseru
And then tear down the door in front of you
itsudemo sou nanda
That's the way it is
wasuregachina koto ga
The things you tend to forget
nani yori mo taisetsuna koto datte
Are the things that are the most important
nani ga machiukete iyou to kamawanai
I don't care what lies ahead
ame nimo makezu yami o terasu
The rain won't stop me from lighting up the darkness
kono kyoujin na kokoro ga areba
As long as I have this strong spirit
kono toki kono basho ni tsudoishi nakamatachi
Friends who gather at this time, at this place
mawari tsudzukeru sekai nanbitotari
The world keeps spinning, No one can stop it
tomo tomeru koto wa dekinai yo
It's convenient
having you around, Tenten!
テレビをご覧の皆さん お元気ですか。
What do you mean
by "convenient"?
私たちも
頑張って張り切ってまいります。
I have convenient tools,
but I am not a convenient tool... okay?
どうぞ 最後まで
よろしくおつきあいください。
No, no! You are absolutely convenient!
Please!
– Umm, Tenten?
– Don't follow me!
I wonder what happened?
I don't know either.
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Tenten's Troubles."
２時間スペシャル。
That was just venting, wasn't it?
オープニングは
この曲からまいりましょう。
北島三郎さん 『北の漁場』。